<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Physical Oceanography Numerical Group (PONG)</title>
    <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://pong-tamu.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People in the Physical Oceanography Numerical Group work on problems in the coastal ocean using numerical simulations. Currently, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.myroms.org/&#34;&gt;Regional Ocean Modeling System (ROMS)&lt;/a&gt; is used for all of the simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/arthur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/arthur/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/dj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/hui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/hui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hui works on estuarine and coastal dynamics, with observational and modelling methods. In 2001-2008, he worked as a PhD student first and an assistant researcher later to develop the saltwater intrusion modeling system in the Changjiang River Estuary. During this period, he reconstructed the framework and I/O rules of the ocean model ECOM-si and introduced the wet/dry and adaptive time-stepping methods. This model has been widely used in the applied and scientific researches till now. Since 2009, he built a Yellow and East China Seas modeling system, created the advection algorithm HSIMT, and developed the de-tiding survey method PAMS. With these new tools and methods, he studied systematically the behavior and dynamics of river plume and coastal currents under a tidal environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/kristen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/kristen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Seattle, but headed east of the mountains to attend &lt;a href=&#34;www.whitman.edu&#34;&gt;Whitman College&lt;/a&gt;, where I received a Bachelor of Arts in Physics and minor in mathematics in 2005. After college, I lived in Washington, D.C., for most of a year before returning to Seattle to attend the &lt;a href=&#34;www.washington.edu&#34;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/a&gt; in my hometown. I received a Masters of Science in &lt;a href=&#34;amath.washington.edu&#34;&gt;Applied Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; in June 2007, and a Ph.D. in &lt;a href=&#34;me.washington.edu&#34;&gt;Mechanical Engineering&lt;/a&gt; in June 2012. I am currently an Assistant Research Professor in &lt;a href=&#34;ocean.tamu.edu&#34;&gt;Oceanography&lt;/a&gt; at Texas A&amp;amp;M University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of academics, I have always been active in the outdoors. I began climbing mountains when I was 15 and have been doing so ever since. In high school I also started playing lacrosse, which I played all through high school and college and hope to pick up again soon. Running has been a part of my life since about 1998. I&#39;ve run numerous half marathons, and completed my first marathon in October 2006 (Marine Corps) and second marathon in April 2009 (Big Sur). I also try to participate in an ultra run once a year somewhere around the West Coast with some good friends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/rob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/rob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rob Hetland is a Professor in the Dept of Oceanography, Texas A&amp;amp;M University. His research is focused on numerical simulation of flow in estuarine, coastal, and continental shelf environments; applications include examining plankton bloom dynamics, formation and destruction of continental shelf hypoxia, and real-time surface current forecasting. For more information, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocean.tamu.edu/people/profiles/faculty/hetlandrobert.html&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/ronnie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/ronnie/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/steve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/steve/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/tingting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/tingting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/veronica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pong-tamu.github.io/authors/veronica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Veronica received her bachelor degree in Oceanography from ESPOL University in Ecuador, and then she attended Gent University in Belgium for her masters degree (2003). For many years her research focused on sandy beach benthos ecosystems in Ecuador, spending her time between field work and multivariate statistical analysis. In 2012 she started working at the Oceanographic Research Institute of the Ecuadorian Navy (INOCAR), were here career path changed. As part of the development of an integrated early warning system for the Ecuadorian coast, she participated in the implementation of a forecast system based on ocean numerical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thrilled by the potential of numerical models, and how they can be used to better understand the dynamics of complex ecological systems, Veronica is back in grad school as a Ph.D student, joining PONG in September 2014. For more information, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vrx-.github.io/&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
